110 Bleecker St. #9F, New York New York 10012

Home: 323 646 7415 - Cell: 323 646 7415 - marlambert@gmail.com

Professional Profile

Innovative, award winning director in music videos, commercials, feature films, television, video games and documentaries since 1982 with 16 feature length films to my credit. Some of these films and projects are listed below.

Technology changes constantly in the film business. I pride myself on the ability to apply my skills as a director with the newest technologies available.

Teaching Experience

- Various experiences as a teacher of film at the graduate and undergraduate level
- Frequent participant on panels and seminars at DGA
- Active member of the Independent Directors Committee at DGA focused on attracting and nurturing young talent into the Guild
- Participant in the Alternative Film Distribution Think Tank at the DGA
- Assistant Arts Professor at Tisch School of the Arts, NYU 2013-2015
- Adjunct Professor at Chapman University,
 Dodge College (Los Angeles): Directing
 Production Workshop 2
- Guest lecturer at New York Film Academy (Los Angeles) 2013
- Master class at Sitges International Film Festival (Spain) 2012
- Taught classes: "Directing the Actor" at USC 1995-96
- Professor at American Film Institute (Los Angeles): "Directing" 1994

Core Accomplishments

One of the trail blazers in the world of music videos and part of a core group which virtually invented this medium and introduced a new era into the world of commercials.

- In the 1980's, one of the few women directors working in Hollywood. (I have always tried to be a role model and to help other women envision themselves in roles of power.)
- Feature film, "Pet Sematary" was the highest grossing film ever directed by a woman. (at the time it was released)
- More recently, the first female to direct a SYFY Original Movie- "Mega Python Vs Gatoroid" 2011.

AWARDS:

- "Miss South Pacific Pageant" many festival awards including BEST FILM at Hawaii Ocean Film Festival and First Runner Up at Woods Hole Festival 2011
- "Siesta" nominated by Independent Spirit Awards for BEST FIRST FEATURE
- "Grand Isle" CRITIC'S CHOICE at Deauville Film Festival
- 4 videos in VH1's Top 100 Greatest Music Videos List
- CANNE GOLD LION and CLIOAward for Arrow Shirt Commercial
- "Dragstrip Girl" nominated for BEST DIRECTOR EMMY AWARDS

Professional Experience

Director

January 2014

Lifetime Network - Los Angeles, CA

"Presumed Dead in Paradise" - TV Movie starring Malese Jow and Olivia d'Abo

Director

June 2012

PBS - Los Angeles, HI

• "Fishing Pono: Living in Harmony with the Sea" - PBS Documentary

Director

December 2010

SYFY CHANNEL - Los Angeles, CA

"MPVG" - TV Movie starring Tiffany, Debbie Gibson & Kathryn Joosten

Director/Writer/Producer

December 2008

FEARnet - Los Angeles, CA

"The Dark Path Chronicles" - 7 part webseries

Director/Producer/Writer/Cinematographer

December 2007

Sundance Channel - Los Angeles, CA

 "14 Women" - Independently produced feature documentary aboiut women in the U.S. Senate. Narrated by Annette Bening

Director

August 2007

• "The Attic" - Independent Feature starring Elizabeth Moss

Director

February 2005

SONY - Los Angeles, CA

"URBAN LEGEND 3" - Feature Film starring Kate Mara

Director

January 2002

DISNEY CHANNEL - Los Angeles, CA

"Halloween Town II" - TV movie starring Debbie Reynolds and Kimberly Brown

Director

February 2000

Warner Bros

"The In Crowd" - Feature film starring Lori Heuring, Susan Ward and Matthew Settle

Director

February 1998

DREAMWORKS - Los Angeles, CA

 "WHEN YOU BELIEVE" - NBC Music Special starring Whitney Houston, Mariah Carey, Byz II Men, Vince Gill, Amy Brant, Wynonna Judd, Brian McKnight, CeCe Winans, and Alison Krause

Director

January 1997

USA Network - Los Angeles, CA

"No Recourse" aka "My Stepson, My Lover" - TV Movie starring Rachel Ward and Terry O'Quinn

Director

February 1996

CBS TELEVISION - Los Angeles, CA

"Face of Evil" - TV Movie of the Week starring Tracey Gold and Shawnee Smith

Director

October 1993

SHOWTIME - Los Angeles, CA

• "Dragstrip Girl" - TV Movie starring Natasha Wagner and Mark Dacascos

Director

September 1992

Paramount - Los Angeles, CA

"Pet Sematary II" - Feature film starring Anthony Edwards, Edward Furlong and Clancy Brown

Director

March 1991

TURNER PICTURES - Los Angeles, CA

"Grand Isle" - Feature Film starring Kelly McGillis, Adrian Pasdar, Ellen Burstyn

Director

October 1989

HBO - Los Angeles, CA

"Tales from the Crypt" - TV series

Director

October 1989

Paramount - Los Angeles, CA

• "Pet Sematary" - Feature film starring Fred Gwynne, Miko Hughes and Denise Crosby

Director

October 1986

Lorimar - Los Angeles, CA

"Siesta" - Feature film starring Ellen Barkin, Gabriel Byrne, Jodie Foster, Julian Sands, & Martin Sheen

Director

March 2011 to November 2011

Visionairemedia - Los Angeles, CA

• Directed American episodes for TRADING PLACES - pilot for reality based series where American students and young professionals trade places with their counterparts from the Middle East.

Director

April 2008 to November 2010

Sundance Channel (USA) & MBC (Middle East - Los Angeles, CA

 Directed episodes for "On the Road in America" - a reality based series following Arabic speaking kids on a road trip across the US

Director/Writer/Producer

February 2009 to October 2010

KAUAI GIRLS

"Miss South Pacific Pageant" - Independent documentary about climate refugees in the South Pacific

Director

December 1981 to October 2000

various record companies - Los Angeles, CA

Directed music videos for the following recording artists (partial list):

Sting, Janet Jackson, Eurythmics, The Gogo's, Motley Crue,

Bobby Brown, Chrissie Hynde, Debbie Harry, The Tom Tom Club, Mariah Carey, Whitney Houston, Allison Krause, Mick Jagger, Robbie Robertson, Live, The Devlins, N'Dea, Rosanne Cash, Lionel Richie, Queensryche, Dolly Parton, Shelby Lynne, Vince Gill, Rod Stewart,

Director

December 1982 to November 1989

Warner Bros Music - Los Angeles, CA

Directed the following music videos for Warner Bros. Music

"Borderline" - Madonna

"Like a Virgin" - Madonna

"Material Girl" - Madonna

"Like a Praryer" - Madonna

"Glamorous Life" - Sheila E

"Dancin" - Chris Isaak

Education

Bachelor of Arts : painting and film

Rhode Island School of Design - Providence, Rhode Island, USA

At the time I attended RISD, there was no degree offered in Film. There was also a lack of interest in narrative painting. To satisfy my personal focus on narrative, in related course work for Painting and Illustration, I directed films and submitted them to fulfill various degree requirements. (I also executed traditional paintings and illustrations.) I was an active member and performer in the RISD Drama Club.